<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Cory Gackenheimer]]></title>
  <link href="http://cgack.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cgack.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-10-21T19:10:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://cgack.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cory Gackenheimer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/10/09/moving-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-09T15:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/10/09/moving-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been toying with the idea to move away from blogger to another blogging engine.  Since I&#8217;ve been doing most of my hacking via Github I have decided to move to <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>.  I have imported all my old posts and hopefully the conversion from HTML to .Markdown hasn&#8217;t caused too much trouble.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud 9 adds Heroku Support]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/09/02/cloud-9-adds-heroku-support/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/09/02/cloud-9-adds-heroku-support</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[One of my favorite online IDEs has added support for Heroku.  This is great news as I have enjoyed developing node.js applications in <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9</a> but felt that the main thing it lacked was a method to deploy directly to the cloud.  So I took it for a test run.  I signed in to Cloud 9 and created a simple hello world app, make sure you use the process.env.PORT to listen on so Heroku can deploy it properly.<br /><br />Commit your changes via the Cloud 9 git interface.Then all you have to do is click the Deploy button in Cloud 9, sign in to Heroku, create your new instance, and deploy.  If you haven&#8217;t created a package.json or Procfile (needed for Heroku deploy), Cloud 9 will create those for you.  My hello world is at <a href="http://cheese.herokuapp.com/">http://cheese.herokuapp.com/</a><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-6512242240963047422?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[github goes ace (and demos)]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/08/25/github-goes-ace-and-demos/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/08/25/github-goes-ace-and-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[A week ago <a href="http://github.com/">GitHub</a> <a href="https://github.com/blog/905-edit-like-an-ace">announced</a> they were incorporating the Ace editor (which powers the <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9 IDE</a>).  Since I am a fan of both Cloud9 and GitHub, I gave it a whirl on my <a href="http://cgack.github.com/">GitHub Pages site</a> and was not disappointed.  As advertised one can easily open a file for editing, preview the diff of your changes and commit.  I think it will likely become useful to edit posts when (if) I finally decide to move my blog from here at Blogger to <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> (just because it looks fun).  For me, this is particularly useful for simple changes like those I have made to my demos and experiments.  Speaking of demos, I had created a simple drawing app using HTML5 canvas for my preschooler which evolved into a demo of the HTML5 History API thanks to a tweet by Christian Heilmann and subsequent read of his <a href="http://hacks.mozilla.org/2011/08/making-history-with-the-august-dev-derby/">blog post</a>.  I decided to use this History API to create the undo/redo functionality that I rely on heavily if i&#8217;m trying to draw something in a painting tool.  As a bonus I added a localStorage call that will recreate your last drawing if your browser closes or you are forced to leave the site for a while.  What does that look like:<br />
<br /> I entered the demo in the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/demos/devderby">DevDerby</a>, you can find it <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/demos/detail/html5-drawings">here</a>.  I hope you &#8217;like&#8217; it too.  (note: I&#8217;ve only really tested my demo on firefox 5, 6, 7, and 8 as well as chrome 13 &amp; 14, so your results may vary if you use a different browser)<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-6571414986215912499?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Dev Tools as an IDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/07/08/chrome-dev-tools-as-an-ide/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/07/08/chrome-dev-tools-as-an-ide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve spent a lot of time trying to find the best development method in Chrome OS.  Recently I decided I wanted to create a chrome extension using Chrome OS.  My first stop was CodeRun IDE which has a sample Chrome Extension project so I thought it would be great for a starter.  The development is pretty mess free, but the problem comes once its downloaded.  It comes downloaded and zipped.  When loading an unpackaged Chrome Extension you can point Chrome to a directory, but not a zipped directory.  So I had to unzip the files&#8230;which was pretty easy to do once I found <a href="http://wobzip.org/">wobzip</a>.<br /><br />Now that I had a skeleton Chrome Extension up and running, I could start to make it my own.  I decided on a simple calculator for starters, plus I thought it might be useful.  I have to admit it had been a while since I&#8217;d used the user &#8216;chronos&#8217; in Developer mode, but once I got it there I found that Chrome OS had a new default text editor (thankfully) in &#8216;vi&#8217;.  This is where it got really fun.  I edited my popup.html file to have a stylesheet and JavaScript file and loaded the html directly in Chrome.  Enter the best web app ever&#8230; Chrome Dev Tools.<br /><br />With Dev tools I am able to make changes to my stylesheets through the inspector to get the style just how I want, then save the modified .css file to the extension directory. <br /> Similarly, I can edit and save versions of my JavaScript file directly from Dev tools.  The only issue with this is when I overlooked some invalid code which prevented Chrome from loading the JavaScript file.  This was not much of an issue the one time it happened to me, as I was able to enter vi and quickly rectify the rogue curly brace and was back to Dev Tools in no time.  So If you ask me what my choice is for rapid JavaScript development, I&#8217;ll say Chrome Dev Tools.<br /><br /> The result from blank files to:<br /><br /><br />and <br /><br /><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-1069319577707889253?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/06/07/i-cloud/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/06/07/i-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier today Apple announced a revolutionary set of services called <a href="http://www.apple.com/icloud/">iCloud</a>.  I must say it sounds incredible to be able to edit a <a href="http://docs.google.com/">document</a>, sync <a href="http://mail.google.com/">contacts</a>, view my <a href="http://www.google.com/calendar">calendar</a>, listen to <a href="http://music.google.com/">music</a>, read my electronic <a href="http://books.google.com/">books</a>, view my <a href="http://www.google.com/picasa">photos</a>, and access my <a href="http://mail.google.com/">email</a> from any internet enabled device. , It does seem like a great advantage to not have to upload to a cloud music service like the Amazon Cloud Player or Google Music, which iCloud offers via iTunes &#8220;scan and match&#8221; and I&#8217;m certain it will be another service I try in my attempt to find the best cloud experience.   I&#8217;ve been happily clouding for some time now, and hope that Apple does good things in the space.  Happy clouding.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-747140899803548158?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chromebook first dibs]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/06/02/chromebook-first-dibs/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/06/02/chromebook-first-dibs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Being a test pilot has some perks.  The latest of which is a special invitation to early released Chromebooks via the Gilt Groupe.  Below is the email I received earlier today inviting me to Gilt&#8217;s privileged offering of the newest Chromebook.<br /><br /><blockquote><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:arial, sans-serif;font-size:13px;"></span><br /><table bgcolor="#ffffff" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="20" style="font-family:arial, sans-serif;font-size:13px;width:400px;"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2" style="font-family:arial, sans-serif;margin:0;"></td></tr><tr><td height="60" style="font-family:arial, sans-serif;margin:0;" valign="top" width="50%"><div style="margin:0;"><img border="0" src="http://www.google.com/chromebook/static/images/email/chrome-173x63.png" /></div></td><td align="right" height="60" style="font-family:arial, sans-serif;margin:0;" valign="top" width="50%"><div style="margin:0;"><img border="0" src="http://www.google.com/chromebook/static/images/email/giltgroupe-110x63.png" /></div></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" height="30" style="font-family:arial, sans-serif;margin:0;" valign="top"><div style="margin:0;"><span style="font-family:Arial, sans;font-size:x-large;"><strong>Be the first to get a Chromebook.</strong></span></div></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" style="font-family:arial, sans-serif;margin:0;"><div style="margin:0;"><span style="font-family:Arial, sans;font-size:x-small;">Since we announced the Chrome Notebook Pilot Program back in December, we’ve been humbled by the amount of interest that we’ve received from users like you.</span></div><div style="margin:0;"><span style="font-family:Arial, sans;font-size:x-small;">We’re excited about the brand-new Samsung Chromebook that goes on sale on June 15. Fortunately, we’ve managed to get our hands on a few machines a little earlier, and we’d like to make these available to you, our biggest enthusiasts.</span></div><div style="margin:0;"><span style="font-family:Arial, sans;font-size:x-small;">When you buy your Chromebook, you’ll also be getting a limited edition, custom-fit Chrome sleeve designed by Rickshaw so you can carry your new Chromebook in style.</span></div><div style="margin:0;"><span style="font-family:Arial, sans;font-size:x-small;">Our good friends over at Gilt, the premier invitation-only shopping site, have agreed to put these Chromebooks up for sale &#8211; but only for a very limited time.</span></div><div style="margin:0;"><img alt="Samsung Series 5 Chromebook" src="http://www.google.com/chromebook/static/images/email/samsung-series5-300x246.png" /></div><div></div></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Duostack acquired by dotCloud]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/05/25/duostack-acquired-by-dotcloud/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/05/25/duostack-acquired-by-dotcloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I wrote about utilizing the Duostack platform as a service to host a Node.js application on the cloud.  Today Duostack announced they were joining forces with dotCloud, another platform as a service provider.  Here is the announcement as I received it:<br /><br /><blockquote><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="background-color:#3b5998;border-bottom:5px solid rgb(59,89,152);width:500px;"><tbody><tr><td style="color:#96a6c5;font-family:Arial;font-size:24px;font-weight:bold;line-height:100%;text-align:center;vertical-align:middle;padding:0;"> Duostack Announcement - May 24, 2011<br /><br /></td>                                         </tr><tr>                                          <td>                                             </td>                                         </tr></tbody></table><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  We are pleased to announce that Duostack is joining forces with DotCloud.</div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">   </div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  DotCloud is a Platform as a Service that provides unsurpassed  flexibility. Developers have the freedom to assemble their own  deployment environment by selecting stack components on DotCloud,  instead of being restricted to a limited stack configuration typical of  cloud platforms. Supported components include PHP, Ruby, Python, Perl,  Java, Node.js, MySQL, Redis, RabbitMQ, Solr, PostgreSQL, and now  MongoDB.</div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">   </div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  As part of DotCloud, we will continue to raise the bar for cloud  platforms and further our commitment as the best place to deploy apps.</div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">   </div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  See the full acquisition announcement here:</div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  <a href="http://duostack.us2.list-manage2.com/track/click?u=54f3e2020e67b0ac9e68cd450&amp;id=06ed5b37c4&amp;e=f3943c1bc8" style="color:#3b5998;font-weight:normal;text-decoration:underline;" target="_blank">DotCloud Acquires Duostack, Expands Footprint in PaaS Market to Further &#8220;One Platform, Any Stack&#8221; Vision</a></div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">   </div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  <strong>What does this mean for apps hosted on Duostack?</strong></div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  Current Duostack developers will receive immediate access to DotCloud. Invite codes will be delivered by email.</div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">   </div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  Apps currently hosted on Duostack will remain online through the end of  June 2011. We will provide assistance for migrating apps to DotCloud.  More information about the transition will be available this week.</div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">   </div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  The Duostack name will be phased out. However, the best parts of the  Duostack platform and the feedback from our beta program will be  incorporated into DotCloud. This starts today as DotCloud launches  support for MongoDB, and there is plenty more to come.</div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">   </div><div style="color:#505050;font-family:Arial;font-size:14px;line-height:150%;text-align:left;">  We are very happy to welcome you to DotCloud.</div></blockquote><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-6112486245904442994?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chromebooks!]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/chromebooks/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/chromebooks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, at Day 2 of Google I/O, it was officially announced that <a href="http://www.google.com/chromebook/#">Chromebooks</a> will be available in retail locations worldwide starting June 15th.  Perhaps even more exciting news was the mention that for Educational institutions (and businesses) these would be available at $20/month/user ($28/mo/user for business) which could be a huge savings (70% over traditional PCs according to the graphic <a href="http://www.google.com/chromebook/#business-education">here</a>). <br /><br />Here is the Keynote from Google I/O day two for those who missed it:<br />[youtube http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MiYND_zvIc0]<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-771895672650425206?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Duostack: Cloud Platform as a Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/05/02/duostack-cloud-platform-as-a-service/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/05/02/duostack-cloud-platform-as-a-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[I have been using and trying many of the all-in-one solutions for web-based development on my Cr-48, but what happens when your favorite editor does not deploy directly to where you want your app to live (<a href="http://c9.io/">cloud9</a>)?  I tried this recently with a <a href="http://nodejs.org/">NodeJS</a> app and a cloud platform (currently in beta) called <a href="https://www.duostack.com/">Duostack</a>.  For my NodeJS app, just as everyone else toying with Node, I <strike>reinvented</strike> reworked the wheel and used Ryan Dahl&#8217;s (creator of NodeJS) basic chat application.  All I did was partition the client to act like it had multiple rooms rather than one group room as in <a href="http://chat.nodejs.org/">the original</a>.  That is not what this post is about. This post is about how easy it is to get a node instance up and running on Duostack.<br /><div><br /></div><div>Duostack is a super easy to use cloud platform as a service for Node and Ruby apps.  Databases that are available by default are MySQL, MongoDB, and Redis (the documentation states external DBs are welcome).  The deployments live on the Amazon EC2 by default, but there is &#8216;cross-cloud reliability&#8217; that will allow for fail over to the Proactive Cloud in case of a <i>possible</i> Amazon outage.  Deployment is as simple as it could get with a cloud platform (well it could get simpler, but its super easy as you can read below). </div><div><br /></div><div>To setup Duostack I had to move away from Chrome OS and into Ubuntu on my Cr-48.  I followed the <a href="http://docs.duostack.com/node/command-line-client#setup">simple steps</a> to get the command line interface installed.  I used the curl method versus the node package manager install and had my Duostack instance configured shortly thereafter.  So now to create a Duostack app.  This is even easier then setup of the command line client, simply type &#8216;duostack create &#8217; and you have it. Duostack uses Git to control deployment so deploying is also a snap, just feed the command &#8216;git push duostack master&#8217; from your git repository, wait a few seconds while Duostack works the deployment magic, and you have your Duostack application deployed.  Mine lives <a href="http://noderooms.duostack.net/">here</a>.  So far I am more than pleased with my Duostack beta access and invite anyone with interest in deploying a Node or Ruby app to a cloud platform to <a href="https://www.duostack.com/signups/new">signup</a> and give it a try.  I have a few other betas for platform as a service solutions to check out, but Duostack got first dibs by granting me beta access before the others.</div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-6022969820459559969?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[changing old habits]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/27/changing-old-habits/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/27/changing-old-habits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[I have been doing a lot of development on my Cr-48 lately.  And as I sit here coding away I wanted to note how useful chrome is to me as a developer.  As I have written about previously there is a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_QI8nj6PSPI">plethora</a> of web-based IDEs to develop with in Chrome OS.  So what I have been finding particularly useful regardless of the development environment is something any chrome user (I&#8217;m talking browser now, not OS) can utilize&#8230;the <a href="http://code.google.com/chrome/devtools/docs/overview.html">Chrome Developer Tools</a>.  Before I received my Cr-48, the majority of my browser based debug sessions lived in Firefox with the amazing and powerful tool <a href="http://getfirebug.com/">Firebug</a>, but thanks to Google I was forced to try something new.  I thought nothing else compared to Firebug (I am not going to speak out against Firefox or Firebug as both are spectacular), but as I have familiarized myself with the Chrome tools I find they are just as powerful and robust.  I love how easy it is to inspect an element on the page and edit CSS and JavaScript, check network events, record a timeline, or just drill through local variables in the console.  So if you are like I was, before you move from chrome to some other tool just to step through your JavaScript in the console, stop and give the Chrome Developer Tools a try, you might decide to stay.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-5974311961422618634?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome OS Everyday]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/16/chrome-os-everyday/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/16/chrome-os-everyday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Writing code in the browser with Chrome OS is an important item for me as a developer and there are a growing number of apps available to get your geek on in the cloud, but what else is awesome on Chrome OS?  Tons of things.  I have been <i>almost</i> exclusively utilizing my Cr-48 since early February at home, with the exception of my taxes (chrome beta/dev wasn&#8217;t supported),  some photo management, the time when the developer build rendered the OS impossible to use (hooray for being a test pilot), and the occasional connection to my remote work computer.  So it is promising that I am able to find a replacement for everything I do on a computer in Chrome OS with limited exceptions.  What else?<br /><div><br /></div><div>I recently have been running some rigorous durability tests on my Cr-48, or I guess I should say Preschooler compatibility tests.  I realized this was needed when I arrived at my son&#8217;s daycare to see a dozen preschoolers huddled around a computer clicking things and learning their letters, numbers, and sequences.  At home my son enjoys the stock windows Paint&#8230; a bunch.  What could I use on the Cr-48?  <a href="http://muro.deviantart.com/">deviantArt muro</a> is a cool choice although it took us a bit to get used to the track pad.  Of course the Chrome web store has many options like <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/mcbkbpnkkkipelfledbfocopglifcfmi">Poppit</a>, a balloon popping game which really tests the durability of the track pad.  But one of my favorite apps is <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/jhfhmaajajcjoijfaceafiembkmhcddc">MeeGenius! Children&#8217;s Books</a>, which reads classic children&#8217;s books out loud and highlights the words as it reads.  Our favorite kid friendly site is and has been the <a href="http://pbskids.org/">PBS kids site</a> which as an avid PBS kids family is full of friendly educational games from our most familiar characters. <br /><br />For me, I have recently been utilizing my Cr-48 to read books on <a href="http://books.google.com/">Google Books</a>.  It may not read super easy in direct sunlight, but I can read at night without a light.  There are tons of books, &#8220;over 3 million&#8221;, which is enough to keep any reader busy for a while.  So there is plenty for everyone on Chrome OS, especially for everyday computer needs.</div><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-4704811775203935933?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ShiftEdit web-based IDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/09/shiftedit-web-based-ide/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/09/shiftedit-web-based-ide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;">I have come to the conclusion that there is plenty of selection for online application development using a web-based development environment.  After trying out several online IDE&#8217;s over the last few months I was asked by a reader to check out <a href="http://shiftedit.net/">ShiftEdit</a>.  I had read that this was an editor of choice for many on some of the Chrome OS forums where the question of what is used to develop on the Cr-48 usually shows up.  So I decided I would try out another IDE to get a feel for how it compares to others I have tried.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;">First off, bonus points for allowing Google (or Facebook) login.  After authentication, this feels like a desktop IDE similar to what I feel like in <a href="http://www.coderun.com/ide/">CodeRun</a>, <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9</a>, or <a href="http://www.akshell.com/ide/">Akshell</a> (I usually test this by going full screen on my Cr-48 and say its good if it isn&#8217;t obvious I am in a web browser).  Selection of file formats is diverse and allows for PHP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Perl, Python, Ruby, Java, or Text with built-in FTP support, which is nice for those who enjoy diverse development.  I tried to create a trivial web page and was pleased with the HTML editor with the exception of when I tried the split view (HTML and Design viewed at the same time) I found it hard to keep the focus on the HTML screen and ended up navigating away from the editor when hitting backspace to delete a <div>.  This is not a huge deal as I would likely not develop full time in split view.  </span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;">JavaScript editing is almost too full featured for my taste by default.  There is an auto complete feature that will auto close brackets in your code as you type.  I found that I was creating double closing brackets so I turned that feature off which was easy enough in the Edit -&gt; Preferences menu.  However,  JSLint is a wonderful addition to any JavaScript Editor, and is fully configurable in the Preferences section (so if you don&#8217;t like to be forced to use === instead of == you can allow that).</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;">A feature that I&#8217;ve recently learned is important to me in an online IDE is allowing for multiple tabs to be opened at once.  ShiftEdit does this well. (I have been working a lot in Akshell for some recent development and the lack of tab support is nearly a deal breaker&#8230;along with the times when I log in and all the open files disappear and I have to select the current project again to restore the view).  There are many other features that I have yet to try in ShiftEdit which could be handy, though I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;ll try them out anytime soon.  Perhaps I will never need to utilize them.  </span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:inherit;">I have found I&#8217;m no longer sure what I&#8217;ll be using as my web-based development environment (most likely a combination of many, just as I develop in a desktop environment).  I am fairly certain I have seen enough for now <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size:x-small;">(of course if you have found &#8220;the best&#8221; one, let me know, I&#8217;ll check it out)</span> that I will be able to find the one (or two, or three) that suits my needs best.  Recently I&#8217;ve been trying all these IDE&#8217;s out and sticking with the current flavor of the week only to later find out certain limitations or something that I preferred in a different editor.  This is no different than using a full featured text editor outside of Visual Studio for example to edit JavaScript or XML files because I don&#8217;t particularly care for the way these appear in Visual Studio.  What I really need or want in a cloud-based IDE is still being defined as each one&#8217;s limitations or offerings reveal themselves through  repeated use.</span><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-9186502508601723025?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud9 revisited]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/03/cloud9-revisited/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/04/03/cloud9-revisited</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[A while ago I <a href="http://go-cloud-go.blogspot.com/2011/03/coding-in-cloud-part.html">tried to use Cloud9 IDE</a> to code in the cloud on my Cr-48 and it was too buggy to even try to accomplish anything in it.  It now appears that the issues have been resolved.  I have been interested in learning some of the awesome that is <a href="http://nodejs.org/">node.js</a>.  I could easily move to my Ubuntu partition, install and build node, and try it there.  However, I really like Chrome OS and I&#8217;ve really been enjoying my other Google V8 JavaScript engine based development with <a href="http://www.akshell.com/">Akshell</a> so why not try Node.js in the cloud too.  Cloud9 is the perfect place for this.<br /><br />First let me say the the github integration with Cloud9 is super smooth.  To start editing a github based project just enter the github url and click &#8220;start editing&#8221;.  So I created a new github repository and started a simple web server with node to see how it would go.  I checked out one of Ryan Dahl&#8217;s (the creator of node.js) introductory videos to get a simple server created in my server JavaScript file.   Then I setup the server configuration in Cloud9 which only required me to tell it which JavaScript file to use and what command line arguments to send it (i.e. &#8220;node server.js&#8221;) to get it running.  Cloud9 does not let you specify a port number like one would in a desktop environment, but they add a helpful hint when running a server &#8220;Important: in your scripts, use &#8216;process.env.C9_PORT&#8217; as port and &#8216;0.0.0.0&#8217; as host.&#8221;  So I modified the server file with the tip, clicked run and sure enough I created a node.js server.<br /><br />I think using node.js on Cloud9 is up to par with any other web-based IDE.  One thing it lacks versus something like Akshell or Kodingen is the ability to deploy to a subdomain directly.  I can however build my app up (if I continue to use Cloud9 versus Akshell) and then deploy to a node.js hosting platform like <a href="https://www.duostack.com/">duostack</a>.  For now I plan on using Cloud9 to learn some node.js and see what things I can make with that.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-764076792241002278?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Better Web-Based IDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/26/a-better-web-based-ide/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/26/a-better-web-based-ide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[After a few days this week without Chrome OS due to <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/chrome-notebook-pilot/biRRijQapdc/FDs_l-29szQJ">a fun error</a> in the Dev build (though its never bad to be able to revert to Ubuntu), I am able to be a Cr-48 nerd again.  The other day one of the three readers of this blog tipped me off on <a href="http://www.akshell.com/">Akshell</a>, another online development environment, which I quickly dove into in order to compare it against some of my other favorites which I have checked out previously <a href="http://go-cloud-go.blogspot.com/2011/02/coding-in-cloud.html">here</a>, <a href="http://go-cloud-go.blogspot.com/2011/02/coding-in-cloud-part-ii.html">here</a>, and <a href="http://go-cloud-go.blogspot.com/2011/03/coding-in-cloud-part.html">here</a>.  By far my favorite has been <a href="http://kodingen.com/">Kodingen</a>, I still go to it to code around and generally geek it up.  This all may change.<br /><br />Akshell is a brilliant development environment that utilizes JavaScript for not only the client-side programming, but also the Server-side.  There are many cool features to how apps are developed and integrated in Akshell, which can be found in <a href="http://www.akshell.com/docs/0.3/">their documentation here</a>.  I have found the environment to be amazing to use utilizing the default &#8220;ak&#8221; library and their Model-View-Controller framework.  For my first test I tried to remake (and improve) the test site I created on Kodingen with Akshell.  I found it was super fast to build with the Akshell environment and enabled me to test and preview just as smoothly as Kodingen though I think the interface with Akshell is much easier to navigate (perhaps because most of the features in Kodingen are still disabled in its current Beta state).  I must admit that I did utilize <a href="http://jsfiddle.net/">jsFiddle</a> to quickly enhance my HTML5 canvas that I had created in Kodingen and then simply copied the JavaScript to Akshell.  So what does a quick Akshell site look like?  <a href="http://gocloudgo.akshell.com/">See mine here.</a><br /><br />One of the promising things about Akshell that I&#8217;ll be getting into soon, is their relational database (PostgreSQL) that is accessible with their &#8220;Simple JavaScript API&#8221;.  From the documentation and the quick test I did with their relation variables I have to agree it is simple to use.  I hope to get some time to get an app going that utilizes this database functionality soon. <br /><br />I don&#8217;t know if I like Akshell an better than Kodingen as far as functionality and features (they both let you code, use a database, and deploy directly within their apps) but I can say that Akshell seems to be a more elegant solution to the online coding environment so I will definitely be using it for my next online coding endeavor.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-884156941911087161?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Heaven with jsFiddle]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/23/javascript-heaven-with-jsfiddle/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/23/javascript-heaven-with-jsfiddle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[I may have finally found the perfect tool to build and test JavaScript concoctions on the fly (or at least a really cool one). I have been utilizing Kodingen (which is awesome) to code on my Cr48 and then flipping between the JavaScript code, css, html (I know I could put these all in the same document but navigating that is more exhausting to me that toggling windows) and rendered pages to test my script, styles, and html quickly.  This can get a bit cumbersome, and flipping between tabs or workspaces can get old very quickly. <br /><div><br /></div><div>So I was reading through the Chromium blog and I watched a video of Paul Irish, a developer advocate for the Chrome team, discussing some of the cool tools using Google Chrome to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nOEw9iiopwI&amp;feature=player_embedded">develop quicker</a>.  This sparked my interest in <a href="http://paulirish.com/">Paul Irish</a> and the first post I saw on his site had an embedded example from jsFiddle.  This led me to <a href="http://jsfiddle.net/">jsFiddle.net</a>.  Perfect.  Clean.  Awesome. </div><div><br /></div><div>The setup of the editor reminds me of the <a href="http://playground.html5rocks.com/">HTML5 playground</a> at HTML5Rocks, only without the need to switch between views of CSS, HTML, and JavaScript.  In jsFiddle the concurrent views of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and the current render are all visible because they are each contained in their own iframe.  I decided to try it out with a quick &#8220;hello world&#8221; test which due to the ease of use and another Paul Irish contribution <a href="http://css3please.com/">CSS3Please</a>, I was able to quickly generate this little fiddle:</div><a href="http://jsfiddle.net/corygack/9gw3k/embedded/result/">http://jsfiddle.net/corygack/9gw3k/embedded/result/</a><br /><div><br />Another great feature is the &#8216;TidyUp&#8217; button which will clean up your code&#8217;s indents and spacing, which is super handy if you are like me and you have moved things around or copied text in from outside sources (css3please).  Also included is <a href="http://www.jslint.com/">JSLint</a> which is a great utility that will examine the quality of your code and &#8220;will hurt your feelings&#8221; as it tells the user exactly what is wrong with their JavaScript.  I used jQuery as my JavaScript library of choice, but also included are Mootools, YUI, Prototype, Dojo, Glow, Procession.js, ExtJS, RightJS,  Raphael, and No Library (pure JS)&#8230; so just about any flavor you might care for.   I am sold on jsFiddle and I will likely be using it as my primary tool to fiddle with JavaScript.</div><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-5181953116803374?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Beatbox in the Sky]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/15/a-beatbox-in-the-sky/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/15/a-beatbox-in-the-sky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I&#8217;ve been trying to find less nerdy things to do on Chrome OS.  I don&#8217;t know if its because I&#8217;ve been boring myself when I analyze new cloud based development environments, or if its because I want to become a better advocate for Chrome OS and its purpose for everyone, but I started playing around with some cool applications.<br /><br />I like music.  I like thinking I am a musician (I know cover bands don&#8217;t really count, but almost&#8230;).  So when I saw in the Chrome Web Store a program from <a href="http://www.aviary.com/">Aviary</a> that would allow me to create music right in my fancy home in the cloud, I quickly installed it.  The interface is super intuitive (i.e drag n drop or click a button), so I was off and running.  There is about any sound you would need for a solid beat including drum kits, guitars, voices, even random sounds from around the house.  My first beat tracks were based off of the standard acoustic drum kit, but I soon moved myself to using <a href="http://www.aviary.com/artists/corygack/creations/claps_snaps_organ">claps snaps and an 8 bit organ</a> (&lt;&lt;have a listen if you must). <br /><br />So Aviary is an amazing website that has loads of amazing artist tools, not just music creation.  They have an audio editor where one can edit and mash together tracks, so the next step is to set up a drum track and try to play some music over the top of it in the music studio (or at least sample some of the creations that are out on Aviary&#8217;s site).  The other tools all seem to be likely candidates for common use for my everyday clouding needs like screen capture and image editing.<br /><br /><i><s>Update:  Shortly after I posted the link to my sample sound Aviary&#8217;s creation listening tool crashed.  I checked a couple creations from other folks and those were broken as well.  I&#8217;ll update again when I see the link is working again.</s></i><br /><i><br /></i><br /><i>Update: the link to the creation should work now.</i><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-3150362873073148523?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RAD with WaveMaker]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/10/rad-with-wavemaker/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/10/rad-with-wavemaker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday <a href="http://www.vmware.com/">VMware</a> <a href="http://blog.springsource.com/2011/03/08/vmware-acquires-wavemaker/">announced</a> they had acquired <a href="http://www.wavemaker.com/">WaveMaker</a>.  I had not explored WaveMaker, but luckily the news exposed this wonderful development tool for me.  WaveMaker is a tool for Rapid Application Development (RAD) that is perhaps the worlds greatest WYSIWYG editor.  Not just WYSIWYG for HTML or page layout, but it can completely eliminate the need for Java coding and with its integrated data structure mappings with <a href="http://www.hibernate.org/">Hibernate</a> it can easily integrate with any enterprise database.  The point is that anyone who is computer capable can write a fully functional web application and maintain it without the need for developer time.  As a bonus, there is integration with the big names in cloud hosting like <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/">Amazon EC2</a>, <a href="http://www.rackspace.com/">Rackspace</a>, Eucalyptus, and OpSource<div><br /></div><div>I checked out the example videos and was amazed.  I was especially excited because I of course noted there was a <a href="http://cloud.wavemaker.com/">cloud version</a> available.   Of course the site is down for maintenance without any idea as to when service would be restored.  Being an avid user or Chrome OS on my Cr-48 I was extremely bummed.  So I decided to  cheat a little (its still browser based app development, however it required installing software) and I cranked up developer mode on my Cr-48 and entered my Ubuntu Linux boot.  I downloaded WaveMaker and kicked it off.  </div><div><br /></div><div>Amazing.  I created a test project with one of the provided templates and started dragging objects onto my web page.  Styling is available at the click of a button, and wiring up events to buttons exposes so special handling can be added.  I can already grasp the power of this tool and I have not spent a whole hour in it.  I can imagine in the coming days and weeks as I get the chance to get more familiar with it, I will be even more amazed.  I am also excited for when the cloud.wavemaker.com site is operational again when the true power of being able to code an application in the cloud and even deploy to a cloud host like EC2 without leaving the comfort of the browser.</div><div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-6275451656771976201?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remotely Coding]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/03/remotely-coding/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/03/remotely-coding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I wrote a review of some web-based tools to remotely control my PC from my Cr-48.  I have to admit that after spending a real work day remotely coding while using my Cr-48 to connect to my PC at work, the win has to go to LogMeIn.  I had thought I could ignore some of the minor issues of TeamViewer because I really enjoyed how simple it seemed, but the character mismatches from what I typed on this end to what resulted on my work PC were not tolerable.  So I think the results should really be that TeamViewer is a simple solution for perhaps remotely helping a relative with an issue on their PC, but for coding remotely, my vote is now entirely for LogMeIn.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding in the Cloud: Part ?]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/03/coding-in-the-cloud-part/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/03/03/coding-in-the-cloud-part</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[&#8220;your Cloud9 beta account has been activated&#8221;.  I had been anxiously awaiting this email (although one can sign up now without a wait period) to continue my quest to find the best coding environment for use with my Chrome OS on my Cr-48.  <a href="http://cloud9ide.com/">Cloud9</a> is another development-as-a-service platform that claims to be the go to solution to marry HTML5/JavaScript development with <a href="https://github.com/">github</a> and has received some decent <a href="http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2381167,00.asp">reviews</a> lately after  its presentation at DEMO Spring 2011.  So I had to login and get coding.<br /><br />I followed the link provided and once signed in I was able to quickly create a new project.  I added an html file and a JavaScript file to create a simple &#8220;hello world&#8221; website to test how the cloud9 development environment worked.  I saved my work, then clicked &#8220;Preview&#8221; and my boring website was previewed in a new tab.  Everything was working well until I returned to my project files and decided I wanted to rename them from untitled.html and untitled.js to test.html and test.js.  Moments later as I was about the check out the &#8220;Run&#8221; and &#8220;Debug&#8221; options mysteriously the screen flashed and the files were once again named as the default &#8220;untitled&#8221;.  I saved the project to return later and investigate.<br /><br />So I signed back in to my account and saw my previously saved project and selected &#8220;Open&#8221;.  This took me to the sign in screen only the styles were all gone and it was a bunch of blank screen with the login box.  I of course had to try again, and after repeating this behavior a few times I thought, &#8220;maybe this is because its a beta account&#8221;.  So I created a new account and thought &#8220;at least I can get a test project started to my testing so I can do a good comparison of cloud9 with kodingen and coderun&#8221; but I was not able to create a project at all.  I tried to use the shared github project that cloud9 provides as an example and that to failed. <br /><br />Apparently cloud9 is getting hit hard with tons of new users who are experience some issues similar to mine, at least according to some of their <a href="http://twitter.com/cloud9ide/">twitter posts</a>.  I&#8217;ll be anxious to get a real review of this cloud based development environment because in my brief time on the inside, it seemed very easy to use and elegantly constructed.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-1003747965081301741?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding in the Cloud: Part II]]></title>
    <link href="http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/02/20/coding-in-the-cloud-part-ii/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cgack.github.com/blog/2011/02/20/coding-in-the-cloud-part-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Coding in the cloud is something I feel I need to be able to do easily now that I&#8217;m utilizing my Google Chrome OS notebook.  <a href="http://go-cloud-go.blogspot.com/2011/02/coding-in-cloud.html">Last post</a> I discussed utilizing an online development environment called CodeRun and found it to be quite useful, but it is not my favorite cloud development environment.  My favorite (so far) is called <a href="http://kodingen.com/">Kodingen</a>.<br /><br />Kodingen is &#8220;The Cloud Development Environment, Online Code Editor, Cloud Hosting, Web-based access to file system, Web-based ftp &amp; svn integration&#8221; or at least it will be all of those things.  Currently Kodingen is in Beta v3 so not all of those features are available as of this writing.  Even though this cloud development environment is not fully operational it is still fantastic.  As shown on their site, there is code support for php, perl, and python [with future support of django, ruby on rails, fastcgi,&#8230;].  The site you create is hosted on Kodingen, and they offer a default 500mb of diskspace, 1000mb of monthly traffic, 1 domain, 6 subdomains, and 5 databases by default (of course you can &#8220;get extra resources&#8221;).  So I set out to play around with Kodingen.<br /><br />Setting up an account was easy enough, so I logged in an got to work.  I quickly <a href="http://gocloudgo.kodingen.com/">created a website</a> with an HTML5 canvas star field plastered on it all from the comfort of my Cr-48.  As far as code editor selection, currently there is support for Bespin, CodeMirror, and Ymacs.  I found that CodeMirror suits my needs best, though I might have been inclined to choose Bespin (probably because of its <a href="http://starwars.wikia.com/wiki/Bespin">name</a>), but it lacks good support for copy/paste in Google Chrome.<br /><br />A couple features I have not utilized more than a simple evaluation are the database support and the image editing.  Creating a MySQL database was a snap (PostgreSQL, and SqLite support to come) so I created a simple database with a couple tables that seemed to perform well enough.  Image editing is currently supported using Pixlr (support for Aviary to come) and again seemed to perform well enough.  Kodingen also reports future support for code repositories such as svn, git, and mercurial where one can create teams to manage joint coding efforts (can&#8217;t wait to try it out).<br /><br />So after my week of trialling CodeRun and Kodingen, I must lean toward Kodingen based mostly on personal preference, but I feel that both systems create a sound cloud based development environment.  As I mentioned in the last post I think these systems would be ideal for educators wishing to introduce their students to web development or as a great code on the go environment.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/7333770831047956364-3314926599229429559?l=go-cloud-go.blogspot.com' alt='' /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
